<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>a concept:website on deblina</title>
    <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in a concept:website on deblina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020 — Deblina Mukherjee — No rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://deblnia.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SCP</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/07/scp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/07/scp/</guid>
      <description>Speedy Scholar is a just-barely-modified fork of Ayman Nadeem&#39;s original open-source project. You can tell it&#39;s a fork because I used the same platform to deploy it (gitbooks) and because I haven&#39;t yet taken out the CS papers that were originally there. I&#39;ll do it eventually.
In case Ayman reads this (unlikely), I should just note that I love the idea of open-source summaries of academic articles. Her book is gorgeous, and if she wants to hang out, I am free on Thursday and she could contact me to hang out on Thursday when I am free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speedy Scholar</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/06/speedy-scholar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/06/speedy-scholar/</guid>
      <description>Speedy Scholar is a just-barely-modified fork of Ayman Nadeem&#39;s original open-source project. You can tell it&#39;s a fork because I used the same platform to deploy it (gitbooks) and because I haven&#39;t yet taken out the CS papers that were originally there. I&#39;ll do it eventually.
In case Ayman reads this (unlikely), I should just note that I love the idea of open-source summaries of academic articles. Her book is gorgeous, and if she wants to hang out, I am free on Thursday and she could contact me to hang out on Thursday when I am free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On &#34;On Self-Respect&#34;</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/06/on-on-self-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/06/on-on-self-respect/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve read Joan Dideon&#39;s _On Self-Respect _ so many times I can practically recite it. That is not enough times, apparently, to understand it. Here is a paragraph by paragraph analysis trying to remedy that.
 Once, in a dry season, I wrote in large letters across two pages of a notebook that innocence ends when one is stripped of the delusion that one likes oneself. Although now, some years later, I marvel that a mind on the outs with itself should have nonetheless made painstaking record of its every tremor, I recall with embarrassing clarity the flavor of those particular ashes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS 154 Notes</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/06/cs-154-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/06/cs-154-notes/</guid>
      <description>These are notes for CS 154, taught by Yanjing Li, Junchen Jiang, and Haryadi Gunawi. The code for the class can be found here.
Lecture 21: Synchronization  Each thread’s program counter points to a different address in the same code segment All threads share data and heap  Data = all static and global variables Heap = malloc’d and dynamically allocated data   Pass by Reference into Main Stack dangerous =&amp;gt; can lead to read / write conflict Think about shared variables and atomicity in concurrency  Which variables are shared?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Statistics Notes</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/06/history-of-statistics-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/06/history-of-statistics-notes/</guid>
      <description>These are notes for History of Statistics, taught by Stephen Stigler.
Boscovich Method  Estimates the parameters of a linear model   Calculate means for each column, and make new column that is [EXISISTING_COL] - [COLS MEAN] Add r (slope) column using the following formula: (Y - Y_MEAN)/ (X - X_MEAN)   This is just the division of the original columns and the column created in step 2  Add d column which is ABSOLUTE_VALUE((X - X_MEAN)) Rank the r colum n such that the largest value has rank 1 Calculate two variables: t = d/2 and h = t/2 Start summing ds by rank, starting with the largest (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Research and Writing Seminar Notes</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/05/legal-research-and-writing-seminar-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/05/legal-research-and-writing-seminar-notes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maverick Markets Notes</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/04/maverick-markets-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/04/maverick-markets-notes/</guid>
      <description>This is a guide to the double-starred readings that will be on the exam.
Hirschman, A., 1986, Rival Views of Market Society and Other Recent Essays. New York: Viking ch.5: Rival Views of Market Society, pp. 105-41  Covers different organizations of economy:  Subsistence Fuedal Capitalism   Interpretation and evaluation of capitalism is historically contingent  &amp;ldquo;The idea that the social order &amp;ndash; intermediate between the fortituitous and the unchangeable &amp;ndash; may be an important cause of human unhappiness became widespread only in the modern age&amp;rdquo; (105) Idea of changing social order to increase happiness is modern Coincides with idea that human actions can have unintended consequences Arguments rooted in existance Precedence of embededness Capitalism evocative (simple models implausible) Response based/dialectec transformation theory   The Doux-Commerce Thesis: commerce is a civiling agent of considerable power and range  According to Hume and Smith, fosters industriousness and assiduity, frugality, punctuality, and probity) Market becomes cetral positon for the satisfaction of human wants   The Self-Destruction Thesis: capitalist society tends to undermine moral foundations on which society must rest  Appeals to individual self-interest over collective interest (Capitalism has within it the seeds of its own destruction) Capitalism throttles all other institutions (commodifies everything)   Eclipse of the doux-commerce thesis  Doux-commerce questioned and set aside in the latte rpart of the 18th century (industrialism wreaked havoc) Durkheim appears to generate a neo-doux commerce thesis, but is aware that any esnse of harmony generated by the division labor was an unintended consequence (superficial at best)   The Fuedal Shackles Thesis  Contends that the capitalist revolution was never finished, left hanging as bourgeoisie market-bearers bowed to the demands of aristocrats and traditional authority figures Less than fully mature capitalist system (peripheral nations from World Systems theory &amp;ndash; these theorists will try and explain why capitalism never matured) American exceptionalism: America came into being without the confines of a feudal past (also a curse according to Hartz &amp;ndash; less ideological diversity)   This is a survey of different conceptions of capitalism &amp;ndash; a coherant but complex analytic (tableau ideologique)  Granovetter, M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS 152 Notes</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/03/cs-152-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2020/03/cs-152-notes/</guid>
      <description>These are notes for the final exam in CS 152, taught by Diana Franklin. The code for the class can be found here.
Data Representation To convert to unsigned binary:
 Number of places is number of bits, fill all with zeroes by default (every place has value of 2 to the power of the place &amp;ndash; from the right, zero based indexing) Find highest power of two that goes into decimal number Go to that power&#39;s place, and change to one Keep adding powers of two until you get to number  To convert to hex:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Science Studies Notes</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2019/12/introduction-to-science-studies-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/posts/2019/12/introduction-to-science-studies-notes/</guid>
      <description>The 16 readings here were the required ones featured on the exam.
Merton, Robert K. 1942. “The Normative Structure of Science,” pp. 267-278   Early text in science studies — analyzing science as an institution, trying to identify norms.
  Merton is an institutionalist (institutions in the sense of trust and behavior) — so studied science as a collection of internal rules and scripts (&amp;ldquo;norms&amp;rdquo;)
 Matthew effect Norms can be studied by sociologist    There are four main norms that constitute science: universalism, communism, disinterestedness, organized skepticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a concept:academic work</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/academic/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m mainly affiliated with the Knowledge Lab, where I&#39;ve been a research assistant since 2018. My research has been supported by the CRASSH Scholars Program, and a micro-Metcalf grant.
Current Projects:
 Programming Languages (w. Jerimiah Milbauer and James Evans) Genesweep (w. James Evans) The Emergence of Political Careers and Parties, New York 1777-1821 (w. Benjamin Rohr and John Levi Martin)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a concept:colophon</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/colophon/</guid>
      <description>This website is a collection of markdown files stored in a Github repository, and deployed via Netlify using Hugo and R&#39;s blogdown package. I bought the domain name from Google Domains for $12/year. This site collects no analytics. If you don&#39;t tell me, I will never know you were here.
The design is forked from bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com, which is a project that originated with @drew_mc. It is 7 CSS declarations and uses your browser&#39;s default accent colors and serif font.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a concept:nonacademic work</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/nonacademic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/nonacademic/</guid>
      <description>2020  Lack of Access, Long Waitlists: Education in Illinois Prisons [Southside Weekly, print edition data visualizations. Feburary.]  2019  UChicago Wifi Ranked #333,333,333 by US News and World Report [Chicago Shady Dealer. November.] Civic Tech in Action [Civicist. October.]  2018  Do You Want A Septum Piercing or Do You Just Want the Cool Bisexuals to Let You Sit at Their Lunch Table? [Reductress. December.] Seven Places You MUST Barf This O-Week [Chicago Shady Dealer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a concept:projects</title>
      <link>https://deblnia.netlify.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deblnia.netlify.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>2020  Speedy Scholar Talk to Dog Bot  2019  Civic Tech Field Guide: Civic Data  2018  HP Avocado Index  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>